A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records, 2001-2009 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records 2001-2009 (bulk 2006-2009)
The Library of Virginia
44689
11.55 cu. ft. (33 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 44694 transferred on 14 January 2010.
Biographical Information
The Executive Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. Members of the Executive Office include the Governor, Chief of Staff, Counselor to the Governor and their assistants. The Counselor in the Kaine administration provided legal advice to the Governor, including liaison with the judiciary and the Office of the Attorney General. The Counselor also provided broader advice to the Governor on political and personal matters as assigned. The Counselor was the chief liaison with the Democratic Party, the Moving Virginia Forward PAC, and outside political constituency groups.
The Counselor was assisted in these responsibilities by a Senior Advisor, a hybrid position, who provided legal assistance to the Counselor and legislative assistance to the Policy Director. The Senior Advisor was available to mediate important policy disputes for the Governor, or with the Governor's consent, for legislators and other external constituents. The following individuals held these positions during Governor Timothy M. Kaine's administration (2006-2010): Lawrence Roberts, Counselor to the Governor January 2006-May 2009) and Mark E. Rubin, Senior Advisor to the Governor and Deputy Counselor (January 2006-May 2009) and Counselor to the Governor (May 2009-January 2010).
Scope and Content
The Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Executive Office-Counselor's Office, Records are housed in 33 boxes. The collection is arranged into five (5) series. Series have been designated for: I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor; II. Judicial Appointments; III. Special Counsel Files; IV. Attorney General Settlements; and V. Files of Lawrence Roberts, Counselor and Shane Emmett, Legal Fellow. These records include agreements, reports, correspondence, e-mail, memorandums, legal briefs, legal files, budget documents, agendas, handouts, meeting notes, and invitations. This collection documents the actions of Governor Kaine's Counselor's Office. The majority of this collection is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1 (attorney-client privilege).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor, 2005-2009
II. Judicial Appointments, 2006-2009
III. Special Counsel Files, 2001-2006
IV. Attorney General Settlements, 2006
V. Files of Lawrence Roberts, Counselor and Shane Emmett, Legal Fellow, 2006-2009
Related Material
Office of the Governor-Tim Kaine
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009). This collection includes the email of Tim Kaine, Lawrence Roberts, Mark Rubin, and Shane Emmett. The Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal provides access to the Kaine email collection and includes guides to other Kaine administration records.
The Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Anne Holton), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Bob McDonnell and William C. Mims), two statewide officials elected in the same cycle as Governor Kaine.
The Executive Orders Digital Collection includes 110 executive orders and 9 executive directives issued by Governor Kaine.
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Policy Office, Records, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009). The Policy Office Records of Governor Timothy M. Kaine are housed in 174 boxes. The collection is arranged into five (5) series. Series have been designated for: I. Decision Briefs; II. Regulations; III. Legislative Files; IV. Executive Orders and Directives; and V. Policy Analyst Files. These records include agendas, decision briefs, correspondence, memorandums, legislative files, briefing books, meeting notes, subject files, reports, talking points and regulations. These records document the legislative and policy priorities of the Kaine administration (2006-2010). This collection also includes records from Governor Mark Warner's administration (2002-2006).
A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Tech Review Panel, 2007-2009 (bulk 2007). The Virginia Tech Review Panel Records, 2007-2009 (bulk 2007), are organized into five series. Series have designated for Files of Virginia Tech Review Panel Members, Files of TriData, Files of Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meagher and Flom LLP, Files of the Office of the Governor, and Freedom of Information Act Request. These records document Virginia's official investigation into the 16 April 2007 mass shooting at Virginia Tech.
Contents List
- I. General Files of the Counselor to the Governor, 2005-2009., Extent: 1.40 cubic feet (4 boxes). (Box 1-4)
  The General Files of the Counselor to the Governor series is housed in four boxes and is arranged alphabetically by subject. This series contains the records of Mark E. Rubin, Counselor to the Governor (May 2009-January 2010) and Senior Advisor to the Governor and Deputy Counselor (January 2006-May 2009). The Senior Advisor was a hybrid position, providing legal assistance to the Counselor and legislative assistance to the Policy Director. Rubin's records reflect both of these roles. The policy related material is open; attorney-client material is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1. Restricted material has been removed from the series and boxed separately (box 4).
  Notable subjects include: electric regulation, indigent defense, wine industry, 2006 budget notes, and appointments for Supreme Court of Virginia and Court of Appeals of Virginia, 2007 (Justice Elizabeth Lacy, Supreme Court, and Judge James W. Benton, Jr., Court of Appeals, retired).
  Notable documents on electricity regulation include: memorandum to Governor Kaine through Mark Rubin from Stephen Walz, Dept. of Mines, Minerals and Energy, 10 January 2006, summarizing current legislative landscape for electric re-regulation; briefing for Governor Kaine on electric restructuring in Virginia, 22 August 2006; memorandum to Governor Kaine from Mark Rubin, 18 November 2006 (draft) and 20 November 2006 (final version), summarizing current legislative landscape regarding electric deregulation; e-mail to Mark Rubin from Stephen Walz, 16 November 2006, containing his thoughts on Senator Clark Hogan's draft legislation; memorandum to Governor Kaine from Hullihen Williams Moore, former chair of the Virginia State Corporation Commission, 3 January 2007 on Dominion Virginia Power Draft Electric Restructuring Legislation; list of members of Electric Utility Regulations Working Group and two e-mails to Mark Rubin from Stephen Walz, 17 January 2007, containing Walz's meeting notes from two January 17 Working Group meetings; memorandums to Governor Kaine from Hullihen Williams Moore, 26 January 2007 and 2 February 2007, on Dominion Virginia Power Draft Electric Restructuring Legislation; memorandum to Governor Kaine through Mark Rubin from Stephen Walz, 14 March 2007, outlining proposed amendments to HB3068/SB 1416 on electric regulation; and recommended changes to Electric Re-regulation Legislation HB3068/SB1416, 20 March 2007. (all b1, f3-4)
  Notable documents on the wine industry include: agendas and notes for HB 1435 Task Force Meetings (b2, f8 and b3, f1)
  Notable documents on the appointments for the Supreme Court of Virginia and Court of Appeals of Virginia in 2007 include: list of candidates under consideration, Mark Rubin's handwritten notes on candidates, outline for selecting Supreme Court vacancy, memorandum to Lawrence Roberts and Mark Rubin from Shane Emmett, Legal Fellow, 31 May 2007, on Governor's authority to appoint judges while Assembly is not in session (b4, f2); and memorandum to Mark Rubin from Andrew Bosse and J. Ryan Harvey, Legal Fellow, 17 September 2007, on Governor's appointment of members of General Assembly to the bench (b4, f3). These records are restricted for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1.
  - Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dual Appointment, 4 June 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Electricity Regulation, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Electricity Regulation, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) Requests, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Indigent Defense, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jurisdiction Swaps (Deed of Cession), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Machinery and Tools Tax, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pay Day Lending, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Gabriel Prosser, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Re-Entry Policy, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Red Horse Settlement, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Red Horse Settlement, 2006-2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Voter Residency, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Wine Industry Issues, 2006 (part one) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wine Industry Issues, 2006 (part two) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wine Industry Issues, 2006 (part three) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - RESTRICTED - DO NOT SERVE
    - Budget Notes, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Judicial Appointments, Supreme Court and Court of Appeals, 2007 (part one) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Judicial Appointments, Supreme Court and Court of Appeals, 2007 (part two) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - SB 817, Constitutional Analysis of the "Choose Life" license plate legislation, 23 March 2009 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Settlement of Case of Dr. Douglas Gross and Dr. Sarah Bissconer vs. John Favret and Dr. Deborah Mazzarella, 2009 (part one) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Settlement of Case of Dr. Douglas Gross and Dr. Sarah Bissconer vs. John Favret and Dr. Deborah Mazzarella, 2009 (part two) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- II. Judicial Appointments, 2006-2009., Extent: 2.45 cubic feet (7 boxes). (Box 5-11)
  The Judicial Appointments series is housed in 7 boxes and is arranged by court (Virginia Supreme Court, Virginia Court of Appeals, State Corporation Commission and Circuit Courts). Judges of the Circuit Court, Court of Appeals, Supreme Court of Virginia are elected by a majority of each house of the General Assembly (8 year terms for Circuit Court and Court of Appeals; 12 year term for the Supreme Court of Virginia). State Corporation Commissioners are elected by the General Assembly for 6 year terms. Interim appointments are made by the Governor subject to election by the General Assembly at the next regular session. Records for each applicant usually include: letter of interest, letters of support, resume, Virginia State Bar Judicial Questionnaire, and Statement of Economic Interest. This series contains confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records and is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78.
  During his administration, Governor Kaine appointed two justices to the Virginia Supreme Court. On 10 October 2007, he selected Chesapeake Circuit Judge S. Bernard Goodwyn to replace Associate Justice Elizabeth B. Lacy, who retired in August 2007. Kaine appointed Virginia Court of Appeals Judge LeRoy F. Millette, Jr. on 15 August 2008. Millette replaced Associate Justice Steve Agee who was appointed in 2009 by President Barack Obama to the 4th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals. Obama also appointed Associate Justice Barbara Keenan to the 4th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in 2009 but she was not confirmed prior to the end of the Kaine administration. Keenan was confirmed by the United States Senate in March 2010. The General Assembly, still in session, selected William C. Mims to fill the vacancy on the Virginia Supreme Court. The Judicial appointments series contains applicant files for the 2007, 2008 and 2009 (tentative) vacancies.
  Governor Kaine made two appointments to the Virginia Court of Appeals. He appointed LeRoy F. Millette, Jr. on 27 November 2007. After Millette's appointment to the Virginia Supreme Court in August 2008, Kaine selected Chesterfield Circuit Judge Cleo F. Powell to fill the vacancy on the Virginia Court of Appeals.
  Kaine selected one State Corporation Commissioner. Theodore V. Morrision, Jr., retired on 31 December 2007. When the divided General Assembly (Republicans controlled the House of Delegates; Democrats controlled the State Senate) could not agree on a selection, Governor Kaine appointed James C. Dimitir on 15 August 2008.
  Notable documents include: memorandum to Governor Kaine from Mark Rubin and Larry Roberts, 17 July 2008, outlining the selection process for a Supreme Court Justice and a State Corporation Commissioner. The memo provides a brief synopsis of each candidate (b11, f8); and letter to Lawrence Roberts from Mark Rubin, dated 6 May 2009, confirming Roberts pro bon legal advice and counsel to the Governor related to the 2007 Virginia Tech shooting (b11, f10).
  - Supreme Court of Virginia, 2007 Candidates
    - Allen, Michael C. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Booker, Lewis T. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Elder, Larry G. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Felton, Jr., Walter S. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Frank, Robert P. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Goodwyn, S. Bernard (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hall, Mary Jane (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hamblen, William D. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Humphreys, Robert J. (filed under 2008 candidates)
    - Kelsey, D. Arthur (see also 2008 candidates) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Langhorne, Arelia S. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mims, William C. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ney, R. Terrence (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Pigeon, Sharon M.B. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Spencer, Margaret Poles (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Starr, Jr., Edward H. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court of Virginia, 2008 Candidates
    - Alper, Joanne F. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Gibb, Colin R. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Horne, Thomas D. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Humphreys, Robert J. (2007 and 2008) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kelsey, D. Arthur (see also 2007) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Millette, Jr., Leroy F. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Padrick, Jr., H. Thomas (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Taylor, Jr., Richard D. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Weckstein, Clifford R. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Wetsel, John E. (recommended by private citizen; Wetsel did not apply) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Supreme Court of Virginia, 2009 Candidates
    - Baskervill, Pamela S. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Edwards, John S. (Supreme Court and United States 4th Circuit of Appeals) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Kemler, Lisa B. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Raphael, Stuart A. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Roush, Jane Marum (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Court of Appeals, 2007 Candidates
    - Friedman, Frank K. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Powell, Cleo E. (see 2008 candidates)
  - Virginia Court of Appeals, 2008 Candidates
    - Morrison, Johnny (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Powell, Cleo E. (also 2007 candidate) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - State Corporation Commission, 2008 Candidates
    - Cramme, III, C. William (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - DeBoer, Jay W. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - De Haas, Philip R. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dimitri, James C. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Fisher, Richard L. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Lake, Julia (part one) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lake, Julia (part two) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lalor, Peter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Maddux, Robert (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Nolte, JoAnne L. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Parker, Allen B. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Taylor, Richard (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Thomas, Michael D. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Walz, Stephen (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Circuit Court
    - 1st District
      - Brown, John W. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Olds, Eileen A. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 2nd District
      - Brydges, James E. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Huff, Glen A. (part one) (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Huff, Glen A. (part two) (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Smith, Chester (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Woolard, Gene A. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - General Correspondence, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 3rd District
      - Sharpe, Jr., Leo Francis (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 4th District
      - Griffith, Charles (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Laibstain, Linda S. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Mahoney, Joan E. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Mathews, James S. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Pearson, Jr., John Y. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - 8th District
      - Phillips, Bradford Carter (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 10th District
      - Candidate submissions (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - 12th District
      - Cogbill, John (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - 15th District
      - Sharp, Charles S. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 19th District
      - Cassidy, Michael J. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - DiGiosia, Lori (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Tran, John M. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Letters of Recommendation, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Letters of Recommendation, Virginia Supreme Court, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - General Correspondence, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - General Correspondence, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - General Correspondence, 2009 (part one) (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - General Correspondence, 2009 (part two) (Box 11, Folder 10)
- III. Special Counsel Files, 2001-2006., Extent: 1.75 cubic feet (5 boxes). (Box 12-16)
  The Special Counsel Files series is housed in 5 boxes. This series documents the appointment of outside counsel to represent state employees and constitutional officers in legal action. Requests for the appointment of a special counsel were sent to the Counselor to the Governor by either the Virginia Department of Treasury, Division of Risk Management or the Office of the Attorney General. The records in this series are for requests from the last year of the administration of Governor James S. Gilmore (2001), the administration of Governor Mark R. Warner (2002-2006) and the first year of the administration of Governor Tim Kaine (2006). Records for each file usually includes: request for the appointment of special counsel, background information on the legal action, detailed legal bills, and requests for approval of special counsel legal fees by the Governor's Counselor (Robert Blue, 2002-2005; Robert Crouch, 2005-2006; and Lawrence Roberts, 2006). This series contains confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records and is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78.
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge J. Robert Stump, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge John C. Quigley, Jr., 2002-2004 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Fathy M.A. Saleh vs. Eddie N. Moore, Jr., et al., 2002-2004 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Woodrow Lewis, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Jean R. Cobbs vs. Virginia State University, et al., 2001-2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - MCI Worldcom - Appeal to Virginia Supreme Court, 2002-2003, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - MCI Worldcom - State Corporation Commission, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hanover Commonwealth's Attorney, Writ of Prohibition, Hanover County Circuit Court, 2001-2002 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Terry W. Givens vs. Joey O'Quinn, et al., 2003 [Request Denied] (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Library of Virginia vs. James S. Gilmore, III, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Robert G. Marshall, et al., vs. Mark R. Warner, et al., 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Interstate Agreement on Detainers, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - John Atkins vs. Commonwealth of Virginia, et al., Services Rendered 24 April-23 June 2006 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Counselor's 15 September 2006 Memorandum to Division of Risk Management concerning retention of Robert Dying in the case of Darick Walker (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Franklin E. Wymer vs. Commonwealth of Virginia and Ronye Davis, 2005-2006 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Loudoun Hospital Center vs. Robert B. Stroube, et al., 2005 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Bernard B. Milbourne, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Gordon Hannett, Virginia Supreme Court (Judge Ray Grubbs), 2005-2006 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Carolyn Jacqueline Whigham vs. Circuit Court, Chesterfield County, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Virginia State Police vs. Susan R. Stevick, Deputy Commissioner of the Virginia Workers' Compensation Commission, 2005-2006 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Appointment for Tevis Brandon-John Atkins vs. Commonwealth of Virginia, et al. (Beaumont Juvenile Correctional Center), 2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Archie Elliott, Jr., 2004-2006 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Paul M. Peatross, Jr., 2004-2005 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Timothy J. Hauler, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Tony Darden vs. Camilla D. Martin, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Ourania Carpenter vs. Dr. Rufus Neville, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Richard C. Pattisall, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge George W. Harris, Jr., 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Carrie Sutherland vs. Judith Williams Jagdmann, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Carrie Sutherland vs. Jerry W. Kilgore, Attorney General, et al., 2005 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Jonathan Moseley vs. Dianna Price, et al., 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Earl Washington, Jr. vs. Kenneth H. Buraker, et al., 2003-2006 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Lynn S. Brice, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge E. Robert Giammittorio, 2003-2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Richard C. Pattisall, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Isaac T. Hockett, III, et al. vs. Johnny R. Acosta, 2003-2005 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Robert Allen Bane vs. Department of Corrections, et al., 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Grandt and Stevens vs. Virginia State University, et al., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Bolling vs. William F. Quillian, III, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Siddiqi vs. Virginia State University, et al. and Upadhyay vs. Virginia State University, et al., 2002 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Joseph Lee Garrett vs. Lt. McClanahan, et al., 2003-2003 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge A. Elisabeth Oxenham, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission vs. Judge Duane E. Mink, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- IV. Attorney General Settlements, 2006., Extent: 0.70 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 17-18)
  The Attorney General Settlement series is housed in two boxes. This series contains copies of settlement agreements between individuals and state agencies requiring the approval of the Governor. The agreements usually include a request for settlement from the Attorney General (Robert McDonnell) which provides the background of the case, an approval of settlement letter from the Governor to the Attorney General, the settlement and other supporting documents. Writs of Habeas Corpus are also interfiled within this series. This series contains confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records and is closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-3705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78.
  - 2006 (part one) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 2006 (part two) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 2006 (part three) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 2006 (part four) (Box 17, Folder 4)